

# Johan Castiblanco

Junior data Engineer Skype: johancastiblanco17

### **Objective**

- Position of software and numeric tools in academic and electric sector studies /Python/Spyder/Pandas/Collab/Kaggle/Matlab/Simulink.
- Electrical applications development
- Windows applications development
- Web applications development.

### **Career Summary**

Junior data engineer with academic experience primary in software development and numeric analysis in this case of optimization and estimation methods like genetic algorithms. This includes architecture, requirement analysis, system design, prototyping, process modeling, system and data modeling, database design, development, implementation, testing and maintenance of software tools. Primary experience in web application services using web technologies as python, C#,JavaScript, and others.

# Key Skills

#### Core Skills

.NET

C#

Spice,Ltspice

Python

Pandas

Matlab

Digsilent

Multisim

Proteus

# Architectural patterns

OOP

### Web Development

ASP.Net MVC

JavaScript

Python

Firebase

HTML5

CSS3

### Windows Development

- Windows Services
- PowerShell
- WinForms

### Mobile Development

Flutter

### Databases, related tools and technologies

- Firebase Cloudstore
- MySQL

### Development methodologies, related tools and technologies

Github

GIT

Gitlab

Trello

Slack

### IDE, Components, Tools:

- Visual Studio
- Spyder
- Simulink toolbox

- Visual Studio code
- Codes Blocks
- Android Studio

### Languages

Spanish (Native speaker)English (B1)

### Career History

#### **Colombia National University / headquarters Manizales**

Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- . Laboratory assistant
  - Use tools and methodologies to create presentations for functions and laboratory guides.
  - Develop high-level product specifications with attention to students' users.

#### **Colombia National University / headquarters Manizales**

Sept.2020- Dec. 2020

- . Teacher assistant
  - Use tools and methodologies to create guides and support academic purposes for electrical and electronic department.
  - Develop high-level product specifications with attention to academic purposes.

### **Certifications**

#### Centro Colombo Americano® English B1+ level,

Jan. 2017

Studying all the courses and the academic standard of the English program

### SENA® systems associate degree,

Nov. 2012

# **Education**

Unal – Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Manizales, Colombia Jan. 2018- December 2020

Master, Electric Engineering (studying)

Unal – Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Manizales, Colombia Jan. 2018- Jul 2019

BS, Electric Engineering

Unal – Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Manizales, Colombia Jan. 2013- December 2018

BS, Electronic Engineering

# References

#### **Diego Alejandro Garces**

Super industry /Quality engineer

E-mail: <u>alejandrogarces22@hotmail.com</u> Mobile (CO): +57 (316) 842 2653

### **Gladys Yolanda Pasuy**

Caldas University teacher E-mail: <a href="mailto:vickypasuy@gmail.com">vickypasuy@gmail.com</a>

Mobile (CO): +57 (316) 842 2653

#### **Vanessa Arias Arias**

Civil Engineer Student

E-mail: <a href="mailto:ariarivane@gmail.com">ariarivane@gmail.com</a>
Mobile (CO): +57 (312) 718 7539

#### **Lisandro Evaristo Castiblanco**

Mechanic Engineer

E-mail: <u>lisacast@hotmail.com</u> Mobile (CO): +57 (300) 610 5984